# AbuBakar Jilani

Frontend Engineer
Total Experience: 2 Years

Highly motivated and adaptive Frontend Engineer. I bring to the table strong skills in communication, problem-solving, logic, and analytical thinking that help corporations increase and maintain their web presence while giving their users a pleasant experience.



abubakarjilani99@gmail.com

+92 317-5869469

Islamabad, Pakistan

abubakarjilani.netlify.app/

linkedin.com/in/abubakar-jilani

abubakar JILANI S

github.com/AbubakarDEV

# **WORK EXPERIENCE (2YEARS)**

# Frontend Engineer (On Site)

www.offsetup.com ♂

06/2021 - Present

Islamabad, Pakistan

Tools & Technologies: ReactJS, NextJS, Redux, Context API, Bootstrap / Antdesign / Material UI, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Twilio, Stripe

#### Responsibilities

- Develop new functionalities and add enhancements in offsetup products i.e. 365sol and Florida-beach rentals.
- Writing code considering SEO and state of-the-art techniques like NextJS, React Hooks, Authentication / Authorization, Validations, Mobile Responsiveness, Material Design, and 2FA.
- Collaborate with cross-functional team to define, design, and ship new features.
- Understand business requirements and translate them into technical requirements.
- · Version control using Git and GitHub.

# Frontend Developer (Remote Job) www.kpibar.com ♂

12/2022 - 03/2023 Madrid, Spain

Tools & Technologies: ReactJS, Redux, Context API, Bootstrap, Tailwind-CSS, NodeJS, Firebase, RXDB, CouchDB

### Responsibilities

- Designing and developing user interfaces, ensuring that they are visually appealing, user-friendly, and responsive.
- Optimizing web applications for speed and performance.
- Collaborating with cross-functional teams, involves effective communication, project planning, and problem-solving.
- · Version Control Using Git and GitHub

## **EDUCATION**

# Bachelors in Computer Science PMAS Arid Agriculture University (BIIT)

08/2018 - 06/2022

Rawalpindi, Pakistan

Courses CGPA 3.4 out of 4

- Programming Fundamentals
- Data structures / Algo
- DBMS

- Object Oriented Programming
- Web Engineering
- Computer Networks

# LANGAUGES / FRAMEWORKS / TOOLS

Javascript (ES 6+) React JS / Next JS

edux / Context API React Hooks

Node JS / Express JS Material UI

Styled Components Tailwind CSS / DAISY UI

Asana Firebase CouchDB / RXDB

Socket.io Git / Github JWT Protocol

## **PROJECTS**

www.365sol.com ☑

NPM / NPX / YARN

• (Next Js | Node JS | Material UI)

www.florida-beachrentals.com

(React JS | Bootstrap)

### 365sol Backoffice

• (React JS | Material UI | Ant Design)

### www.kpibar.com 🗷

• (React JS | Tailwind Css / Daisy UI)

## **LANGUAGES**

### English

Professional Working Proficiency

### Urdu

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

### Punjabi

Native or Bilingual Proficiency